Guide to the K.O. Friedrichs Collection on Richard Courant MC.384
New York University Archives
K.O. Friedrichs Collection on Richard Courant
1920-1980
New York University Archives
Friedrichs, K. O. (Kurt Otto), 1901-1983
Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences
Friedrichs, Martin
MC.384
.5 linear feet in 1 manuscript box
K.O. (Kurt Otto) Friedrichs was a German American mathematician who co-founded the Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences at New York University. The K.O. Friedrichs Collection on Richard Courant (dated 1920-1980) consists of materials collected by Friedrichs documenting the life and career of Richard Courant. Materials include correspondence, speeches given in Courant's honor (including his memorial), reprints of conference proceedings and articles written by Courant (many in German), publications by other mathematicians, and summaries of visits to Germany.
Scope and Contents
The K.O. Friedrichs Collection on Richard Courant (dated 1920-1980) consists of materials collected by Friedrichs documenting the life and career of Richard Courant. Materials include correspondence, speeches given in Courant's honor (including his memorial), reprints of conference proceedings and articles written by Courant (many in German), publications by other mathematicians, and summaries of visits to Germany.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was treated as an administrative transfer to the New York University Archives from the Courant Institute in the summer of 2023 when the Courant Institute Library closed. The accession number associated with this transfer is 2023.044.
Biographical Note
K.O. (Kurt Otto) Friedrichs was a German American mathematician who co-founded the Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences at New York University.
Custodial History
Given to the Courant Institute Library by Martin Friedrichs, year unknown.
Mathematicians; Mathematicians, German; Applied mathematics.; Mathematics |x Study and teaching.; Courant, Richard, 1888-1972; Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences; Friedrichs, Martin
- American Institute of Physics, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bibliography, circa 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Birthdays, 1948-1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Constance Reid, 1968-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence with Herman Weyl, 1938-1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Courant Memorial Lectures, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Lemma, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Science in Germany, 1947-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Stifungs Lehrstul Speech, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Reprints, 1920-1928 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- Reprints, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Reprints, 1936-1956 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)